good evening I'm Martha Raddatz from ABC
News and I'm Anderson Cooper from CNN we
want to welcome you to Washington
University in st. Louis for the second
presidential debate between Hillary
Clinton and Donald Trump sponsored by
the Commission on Presidential Debates
tonight's debate is a Town Hall format
which gives voters a chance to directly
ask the candidates questions Martha and
I will ask follow-up questions but the
night really belongs to the people in
this room and to people across the
country who have submitted questions
online the people you see on this stage
were chosen by the Gallup Organization
they are all from the st. Louis area and
told Gallup they haven't committed to a
candidate each of them came here with
questions they want to ask and we saw
those questions for the first time this
morning Anderson and I and our team from
ABC and CNN are the only ones who have
seen them both candidates will have two
minutes to answer each audience and
online question we hope to get to as
many questions as we can so we've asked
the audience here not to slow things
down with any applause except for now
ladies and gentlemen the Republican
nominee for president Donald J Trump and
the Democratic nominee for president
Hillary Clinton
[Applause]
thank you very much for being here we're
gonna begin with a question from one of
the members in our Town Hall
each of you will have two minutes to
respond to this question Secretary
Clinton you won the coin toss so you'll
go first our first question comes from
Patrice brach the trees thank you and
good evening the last presidential
debate could have been rated as ma
mature audiences per TV parental
guidelines knowing that educators design
viewing the presidential debates as
students homework
do you feel you're modeling appropriate
and positive behavior for today's youth
well thank you are you a teacher yes I
think that that's a very good question
because I've heard from lots of teachers
and parents about some of their concerns
about some of the things that are being
said and done in this campaign and I
think it is very important for us to
make clear to our children that our
country really is great because we're
good and we are going to respect one
another lift each other up we are going
to be looking for ways to celebrate our
diversity and we are going to try to
reach out to every boy and girl as well
as every adult to bring them in to
working on behalf of our country I have
a very positive and optimistic view
about what we can do together that's why
the slogan of my campaign is stronger
together because I think if we work
together if we overcome the divisive
nough stats sometimes sets Americans
against one another and instead we make
some big goals and I've set forth some
big goals getting the economy to work
for everyone not just those at the top
making sure that we have the best
education system from preschool through
college and making it affordable and so
much else if we set those goals and we
go together to try to achieve them
there's nothing in my opinion that
America can't do so that's why I hope
that we will come together in this
campaign
I'm hoping to earn your vote I'm hoping
to be elected in November and I can
promise you I will work with every
American I want to be the president for
all Americans regardless of your
political beliefs where you come from
what you look like your religion I want
us to heal our country and bring it
together because that's I think the best
way for us to get the future that our
children and our grandchildren deserve
Secretary Clinton thank you mr. Trump
you have two minutes well I actually
agree with that I agree with everything
she said I began this campaign because I
was so tired of seeing such foolish
things happen to our country this is a
great country this is a great land I've
gotten to know the people of the country
over the last year and a half that I've
been doing this as a politician I could
not believe I'm saying that about myself
but I guess I have been a politician and
my whole concept was to make America
great again when I watch the deals being
made when I watch what's happening with
some horrible things like Obamacare were
your health insurance and health care is
going up by numbers that are
astronomical 68% fifty-nine percent
seventy one percent when I look at the
Iran deal and how bad a deal it is for
us it's a one sided transaction where
we're giving back a hundred and fifty
billion dollars to a terrorist state
really the number one terrorist state
we've made them a strong country from
really a very weak country just three
years ago when I look at all of the
things that I see and all of the
potential that our country has we have
such tremendous potential whether it's
in